Register of the Richard Thomas Kennedy papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- NRC THREE MILE ISLAND INVESTIGATIONS, 1976-1980
  - General
    - Press releases, 1979 April 11-1980 April 17 (Box-folder 68: 6)
    - Reports
      - General. Weekly Status Reports, 1980 March 11-June 23 (Box-folder 68: 7)
      - "Evaluation of Long-term Post Accident Core Cooling of Three Mile Island Unit 2" (NUREG-0557), 1979 April (Box-folder 68: 8)
  - Accident sequence. Chronologies, memoranda, hearing transcript and statement, 1979 ca. March-May (Box-folder 69: 1-3)
  - Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards
    - General. Includes letter and report to the Rogovin Commission relating to ACRS recommendations, 1979 July 25 (Box-folder 69: 4-7)
    - Hearing transcripts
      - General meetings, 1979
        - (Meeting #228), April 5 (Box-folder 70: 1-3)
        - (Meeting #229), May 10
        - (Meeting #229, contd.), May 11-12 (Box-folder 71: 1-3)
        - (Meeting #230), June 14
        - (Meeting #230, contd.), June 15 (Box-folder 72: 1)
      - Special meetings, 1979 April 16-17 (Box-folder 72: 2-3)
      - TMI Subcommittee meetings, 1979 (Box 73)
        - April 4-May 1 (Box-folder 73: 1-4)
        - May 9 and May 31 (Box-folder 74: 1-2)
        - June 1-7 (Box-folder 75: 1-4)
        - July 9-27 (Box-folder 76: 1-4)
        - Aug. 8-Sept. 5 (Box-folder 77: 1-2)
  - Babcock and Wilcox. Primarily post-TMI re-evaluation of generic design and sister plants
    - General. Other reactors
      - General
        - 1979 April (Box-folder 77: 3-4)
        - 1979 May (Box-folder 78: 1)
      - Davis Besse (Ohio), NOTE: A very similar accident occurred here yet was recognized and controlled, 1976 Nov.-1979 July. 1977 Sept. 24 (Box-folder 78: 2-3)
      - Oconee (South Carolina), 1978 April-1979 June (Box-folder 78: 4)
      - Rancho Seco (California), 1979 April 1-19. (Box-folder 78: 5)
        Includes correspondence with Gov. Edmund Brown, Jr.
    - C. Michelson, "Decay Heat Removal during a Very Small Breack LOCA for a B&W 205-Fuel-Assembly PWR", 1978 Jan. (Box-folder 78: 6)
    - "Staff Report on the Generic Assessment of Feedwater Transients in Pressurized Water Reactors Designed by the B&W Company" (NUREG-0560), 1979 May (Box-folder 78: 7)
  - Corrective actions. Consists of TMI Lessons Learned Task Force recommendations and the subsequent development of an Action Plan for more general reactor regulation reform
    - Includes a report entitled "TMI Lessons Learned Task Force Status Report and Short-term Recommendations" (NUREG-0578), and a transcript sent to the NRC by the President's Commission for licensing review purposes, 1979 April-Sept. July; Aug. 23 (Box-folder 79: 1-7)
    - Includes a memorandum with a transcript of a briefing by Harold Denton on the conclusions of the task force, a draft report entitled "Report to the Director, Office of Inspection and Enforcement on Lessons Learned from Three Mile Island by Special Review Group, OIE" (NUREG-0616), a final report entitled, "TMI-2 Lessons Learned Final Report", Oct.; a report entitled "Supplement to Staff Position on Need to Consider Class 9 Events," which relates to a general re-evaluation of major accident factors, including appendices on the NRC Action Plan, siting and design, emergency preparedness and radiation effects, 1979 Sept.-1980 May. 1979 Sept. 6; Oct. 10; 1980 March (Box-folder 80: 1-9)
  - Decontamination and clean-up of the TMI-2 reactor
    - 1979 April-Dec. (Box-folder 81: 1-7)
    - Includes materials relating to public meetings held in Pennsylvania, 1980 Jan.-June. March 19 and 21 (Box-folder 82: 1-7)
  - Economic effects
    - Extraordinary Nuclear Occurrence (ENO). Relates to the discussion concerning application of this designation to the TMI accident, thus qualifying under the Price-Andersen Act to provide payment for any resulting claims (Box-folder 82: 8)
    - Financial qualification review, 1980 Feb.-March (Box-folder 83: 1)
  - Emergency response procedures
    - Emergency planning, 1979 April-Sept. (Box-folder 83: 2-5)
    - Evacuation plans, 1979 April (Box-folder 83: 6)
    - Interagency Radiological Assistance Program (IRAP), 1979 April (Box-folder 83: 7-8)
  - Environmental effects. Primarily a report (NUREG-0596), 1979 Oct.-1980 April (Box-folder 84: 1)
  - General Public Utilities/Metropolitan Edison. Relates primarily to issues of management competence and the restart of the undamaged TMI-1 reactor, Includes public meeting, 1979 June-1980 March. 1980 Jan. 9
    - Includes an interim report submitted by Met. Ed. with cover memorandum and a Safety Evaluation order modifying operating license, 1979 June-1980 Jan. dated Aug. 9; ca. Sept. (Box-folder 84: 2-7)
    - 1980 Jan.-March (Box-folder 85: 1-2)
  - International reactions, 1979 April-1980 Feb. (Box-folder 85: 3)
  - Investigation and enforcement
    - General, Includes some material relating to allegations by Harold W. Hartman, Jr., 1979 March-1980 May. (Box-folder 85: 4-7)
    - "Investigation into the March 28, 1979 Three Mile Island Accident by Office of Inspection and Enforcement" (NUREG-0600) (Box-folder 86: 1)
  - Legal issues. Relates largely to records management and FOIA requests, 1979 April-1980 May (Box-folder 86: 2-3)
  - Radiation health effects
    - 1979 April-May (Box-folder 86: 4-5)
    - 1979 June-1980 April (Box-folder 87: 1-6)
  - Social and psychological effects, Includes a report entitled, "The Social and Economic Effects of the Accident at Three Mile Island" (NUREG/CR-1215), 1979 July-1980 May. (Box-folder 87: 7-8)
  - Technical systems
    - General. Other reactors (non-Babcock & Wilcox), 1979 April (Box-folder 88: 1)
    - Hydrogen bubble, Includes a report on hydrogen/oxygen generation rate during the accident, 1979 June-Sept. 1979 June (Box-folder 88: 2-6)
    - In-core thermocouples, 1979 Sept.-Nov. (Box-folder 88: 7)
    - Instrumentation, 1979 April-Dec. (Box-folder 88: 8)
    - Oak Ridge Laboratories technical support, 1979 July-Sept. (Box-folder 88: 9)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1976-1980.
  SEE ALSO: NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION OFFICE FILES/Speeches/Background materials
  - Atomic Industrial Forum, Inc. (AIF) (Box-folder 89: 1-6)
    - General, Letters, memoranda, notes, reports on licensing problems, and a transcript of a meeting with the NRC, 1976 Oct.-1979 March.
    - Conference reports, ca. 1976-1980
  - Economics of nuclear energy
    - General, Memoranda, reports, and hearing testimony, 1977 Aug.-1979 Sept. (Box-folder 89: 7-8)
    - Anti-trust review process. Memoranda, reports, and letters, 1977 Feb.-1979 Sept. (Box-folder 90: 1)
  - Energy policy and projections. Primarily speeches, reports and printed articles, Includes a survey report by Louis Harris & Associates, Inc., 1974 Nov.-1980 April. 1978 Dec. (Box-folder 90: 2-5)
  - Solar studies. Letters relating to a proposed study, 1978 April (Box-folder 90: 6)
- PHONOTAPES.
  - 1 phonotape (reel-to-reel) of a speech given in Madrid by Richard Kennedy, 1979 Nov. 5
- PHONOTAPE CASSETTES.
  - 16 cassettes of the American Law Institute-American Bar Association Second Annual Program on Nuclear Export Control, Washington, D.C., 1979 March.
    Access
    Use copy reference number: 83063_a_0011751
  - 1 cassette of a song by Bea Godfney, "God Bless Solar Energy"
- PHOTOGRAPHS.
  - See photo card catalog for description (Cabinet 10.A-V)
- VIDEOCASSETTES.
  - Two videocassettes made during a trip to Korea in 1978 March: an interview with Richard Kennedy entitled "Nuclear Energy and Nonproliferation", and a speech by Richard Kennedy entitled "United States Nonproliferation Policy"
- RESTRICTED MATERIALS, 1975-1980
  (* indicates subsequent NRC review)
  - General
    - General. Includes miscellaneous material relating to the restriction of these documents (Box-folder 91: 1)
    - Adjudicatory items relating to: 1) restricted data procedures; 2) certiorari system for the Commission; 3) use of cameras during NRC licensing hearings; 4) SECY-A-75-24; 5) reactor site criteria. Reports and memoranda, 1975 March-1976 August. (Box-folder 91: 2)
      - 3) Returned to collection as per NRC Public Documents print-out
      - 4) Expurgated copy returned to collection as per NRC letter, 1987 July 30
      - 5) Original returned to collection as per NRC letter, 1987 July 30
    - Review of ALAB-268, Southern California Edison Co., San Onofre. Policy report, 1975 May 9. (Box-folder 91: 3)
    - Clinch River Breeder Reactor (SECY A-76-45 and ALAB-330). Report prepared for Commissioner Kennedy by Richard Stratford, 1975 May 25. (Box-folder 91: 4)
    - Miscellaneous contracts of interest. Note, ca. 1975 June-July. (Box-folder 91: 5)
    - Signing of NRC/FMI arrangement for nuclear facilities safety cooperation. Summary telex (?) message relating to IAEA meeting in Vienna, 1975 Sept. 4. (Box-folder 91: 6)
    - Opinion on petition for intervention and hearing on Tarapur, India export license (SECY-A-76-40). Memorandum/report from Peter Strauss, General Counsel, 1976 May 6. (Box-folder 91: 7)
    - Memorandum from Commissioner Kennedy to Ken Chapman relating to safeguards, 1976 May 16. (Box-folder 91: 8)
    - Summary information on FBI conference re: Bicentennial weekend with letter from Director, Civil Aviation Security Service. Memorandum relating to possible terrorist activities, 1976 June 19. (Box-folder 91: 9)
    - Commission review of NEPA issues presented by the Clinch River Breeder Reactor project. Memorandum/report from Peter L. Strauss, General Counsel, 1976 June 28. (Box-folder 91: 10)
    - Export Reorganization Act (S. 1439): Next Steps. Memorandum from Ben Huberman for the Commission, 1976 July 13. (Box-folder 91: 11)
    - Comments on the August 31 version of the Safeguards supplement. Memorandum from Commissioner Kennedy to Ben Huberman, 1976 Sept. 10. (Box-folder 91: 12)
    - Comments on the draft DES Safeguards Supplement Cost Benefit Analysis. Memorandum from Commissioner Kennedy to Ben Huberman, 1976 Sept. 22. (Box-folder 91: 13)
    - Export Licensing Review. Memorandum and draft report from James R. Shea to the Commission. Expurgated copy returned to collection as per NRC letter, 1976 Nov. 5. 1987 July 30 (Box-folder 91: 14)
    - Draft summary of Export Licensing Study. Memorandum and draft summary from James R. Shea to the Commission, 1976 Nov. 10. (Box-folder 91: 15)
    - Draft Export Licensing Study: Next Steps. Memorandum and outline of proposed export licensing rule from Ben Huberman to the Commission, 1976 Nov. 29. (Box-folder 91: 16)
    - "Nuclear Energy's Dilemma: Safely Disposing of High Level Radioactive Wastes". Partial draft GAO report previously attached to testimony by Clifford V. Smith before the Udall Committee, 1977 ca. May 16. (Box-folder 91: 17)
    - Additional guidance--Policy on Alternative Site Evaluations (SECY-77-433). Memorandum from Samuel J. Chilk (Secretary) to Lee V. Gossick (Executive Director for Operations) with attached policy statement. Expurgated copy returned to collection as per NRC letter of 1987 July 30, 1977 Nov. 3. (Box-folder 91: 18)
    - Report on discussions with foreign officials during trip to Far East, Report with cover memorandum from Joseph D. Lafleur, Jr. (Office of International Programs) to Commissioner Kennedy, 1978 April 21. 1978 March 9-24. (Box-folder 91: 19)
    - NRC staff comments on proposed export of special nuclear materials to India for the Tarapur Atomic Power Station. Legal document, 1979 Jan. 11. (Box-folder 91: 20)
    - N. C. Menon report on NRC consideration of Tarapur fuel license. State Department dispatch, 1979 June 16. (Box-folder 91: 21)
    - State Department response to questions on proposed export to India, XSNM-1379. Information report, 1979 July 12. (Box-folder 91: 22)
    - Westinghouse FOIA request. Memorandum from Commissioner Kennedy for Carlton R. Stoiber (Assistant General Counsel) with attachments of earlier materials, 1979 July 23. (Box-folder 91: 23)
    - Staff requirements--affirmation session 79-29. Memorandum with attachments from Samuel Chilk to Lee V. Gossick and Leonard Bickwit, Jr. (General Counsel), 1979 Oct. 12. (Box-folder 91: 24)
    - Staff organization. Memorandum from Commissioner Kennedy to the Commission, 1979 Dec. 7. (Box-folder 91: 25)
    - Draft GAO letter report to Senators Hart and Simpson on NRC's actions to implement TMI recommendations. Memorandum from James J. Cummings (Director, Office of Inspector and Auditor) to William J. Dircks (Executive Director for Operations). Original returned to collection as per NRC letter, 1980 May 9. 1987 July 30 (Box-folder 91: 26)
  - Three Mile Island transcripts
    - (two versions), 1979 March 30 (Box-folder 92: 1-2)
    - 1979 March 31 (Box-folder 92: 3)
    - 1979 April 16 (Box-folder 92: 4)
    - (with memorandum). Partial expurgated copy returned to the collection as per NRC letter, 1979 April 17 1987 July 30 (Box-folder 92: 5-6)
    - 1979 April 18 (Box-folder 92: 7)
    - (two versions), 1979 April 23 (Box-folder 92: 8-9)
    - (with memorandum). Partial expurgated copy returned to the collection as per NRC letter, 1979 April 24 1987 July 30 (Box-folder 92: 10)
    - 1979 May 11 (Box-folder 92: 11)
    - 1979 June 13 (Box-folder 92: 12)
- DECLASSIFIED U.S. GOVERNMENT RECORDS, 1975-2017
  - Records released in 2010, 1976
  - Records release in 2017, 1975-2017